Tae-Gyeong. Tae-Gyeong, hold on.
แทกยอง แทกยอง เดี๋ยวก่อน
Are you upset?
อารมณ์เสียใช่ไหม
Yes.
ครับ
I'm sorry. I should've discussed this with the kids first.
ขอโทษนะ ครูน่าจะคุยกับเพื่อนคนอื่นก่อน
I was too eager.
ครูใจร้อนไปหน่อย
Even though Shin-Woo talks like that, he's not a bad kid.
ถึงชินอูจะพูดจาแบบนั้น แต่ก็ไม่ได้คิดร้ายอะไรหรอก
He's a good kid once you get to know him.
ถ้าสนิทกันจะรู้ว่าเขาเป็นเด็กดี
I don't care to be friends with him.
ผมไม่อยากสนิทกับเขา
I've never even had a friend before, so how can I join the student council?
ผมไม่เคยมีเพื่อน แล้วจะเข้าสภานักเรียนได้ยังไง
I'll just pretend this never happened.
ผมจะทำเป็นไม่เคยเกิดขึ้นแล้วกันครับ
Thank you for worrying about me.
ขอบคุณที่เป็นห่วงนะครับ
Tae-Gyeong. You told me...
แทกยองเคยบอกใช่ไหม
that you wanted to change.
ว่าอยากเปลี่ยนตัวเอง
You've already changed.
ตอนนี้เธอเปลี่ยนไปแล้วนะ
The person you were would never have come up to me.
ถ้าเป็นแทกยองคนเดิม คงไม่มีทางมาหาครูหรอก
I was really moved because you came to me.
ครูประทับใจจริง ๆ ที่เธอมาหา
So since you've changed,
ในเมื่อเธอเปลี่ยนไปแล้ว
shouldn't you try at least once?
จะไม่ลองสักครั้งเหรอ
I still have no idea...
(ฉันยังไม่รู้เลย)
what I was thinking at the time.
(ว่าตอนนั้นคิดอะไรอยู่)
Why did I decide to become...
(ทำไมฉันถึงตัดสินใจเป็นอีกคน)
a different person overnight?
(ในชั่วข้ามคืน)
If you don't want to, there's nothing I can do.
ถ้าไม่อยากทำ ครูก็ทำอะไรไม่ได้
I'm sorry for bringing it up.
ครูไม่น่าพูดขึ้นมาเลย
- Let's just pretend this... - I'll do it.
- คิดซะว่า... - ผมจะทำครับ
I'll make an effort.
ผมจะพยายามครับ
Okay. Just once. Let's try one time.
โอเค แค่ครั้งเดียว เราลองดูสักครั้งนะ
I'll support the new Tae-Gyeong too.
ครูก็จะสนับสนุนแทกยองคนใหม่เหมือนกัน
Maybe it's because...
(อาจเป็นเพราะ)
someone gave me a hand...
(มีคนยื่นมือมาหาฉัน)
for the first time.
(เป็นครั้งแรก)
(Administration)
(ห้องสภานักเรียน)
My gosh.
ปังมาก
It's cleaner than my room.
สะอาดกว่าห้องฉันอีก
We must have a snail bride in the student council room.
คงมีเจ้าสาวหอยทากในห้องสภานักเรียนแน่เลย
Are you going to leave him be?
จะปล่อยเขาไปแบบนั้นเหรอ
What are you talking about?
อะไรล่ะ
He's making an effort. Are you really not going to accept him?
เขาพยายามซะขนาดนี้ นายจะไม่รับจริงเหรอ
Who told him to make an effort?
ใครสั่งให้ทำล่ะ
Why did he do something we didn't ask for?
ทำไมต้องเจ๋อด้วย
Wouldn't it be nice to have a member who is as honest and eloquent as Tae-Gyeong?
ถ้ามีสมาชิกที่ซื่อสัตย์ และพูดเก่งอย่างแทกยองก็น่าจะดีไม่ใช่เหรอ
Based on this, he's neat and diligent too.
ดูจากตอนนี้ เขาเป็นคนเนี้ยบและขยันด้วย
What are you talking about? You could tell he'll be tiresome and sensitive.
พูดอะไรน่ะ ดูก็รู้ว่าน่าเหนื่อยหน่ายและอ่อนไหวง่าย
Gosh, he can't be as bad as Noh Shin-Woo.
โธ่ จะสู้โนชินอูไหวเหรอ
Gosh.
เดี๋ยวปั๊ด
In any case, I have no intention on changing my mind.
ยังไงก็เถอะ ผมไม่คิดจะเปลี่ยนใจ
Why do you hate him so much?
ทำไมถึงเกลียดเขานักล่ะ
- Did something happen between you? - Is that it?
- พวกนายมีเรื่องอะไรกันเหรอ - มีเหรอ
No. I just don't like him.
ไม่มี ก็แค่ไม่ชอบ
Your default is apathy. But...
นายเป็นพวกไร้อารมณ์อยู่แล้ว แต่...
the fact that you hate him for no reason...
ที่เกลียดเขาทั้งที่ไม่มีเหตุผล...
Do you need a reason for hating someone?
จะเกลียดใครต้องมีเหตุผลด้วยเหรอ
Be honest. You feel bad, right?
บอกมาตรง ๆ แอบรู้สึกผิดใช่ไหม
You shouldn't have said you hated him so much.
นายไม่น่าพูดว่าเกลียดเขาขนาดนั้น
You regret it, and it bothers you, right?
ก็เลยเสียใจ แล้วมันก็กวนใจใช่ไหม
- No. - Gosh.
- เปล่าสักหน่อย - แหม
We can hear you rolling your eyes.
เราได้ยินเสียงตาล่อกแล่กนะ
You feel bad, right?
รู้สึกผิดล่ะสิ
Why should I feel bad? He said he doesn't like me either.
ทำไมฉันต้องรู้สึกผิดด้วย เขาก็ไม่ชอบฉันเหมือนกัน
Oh, I see.
อ๋อ
So you don't like him because he doesn't like you?
สรุปว่านายไม่ชอบเขา เพราะเขาไม่ชอบนายสินะ
Goodness. Were your feelings hurt?
โถ เสียความรู้สึกเหรอ
What are you talking about? Gosh.
พูดเรื่องอะไรน่ะ ชิ
Where are you going?
จะไปไหนเนี่ย
I'm going to the bathroom.
ไปห้องน้ำ
The appearance of a snail bride in the peaceful student council room.
การปรากฏตัวของเจ้าสาวหอยทาก ในห้องสภานักเรียนที่สงบสุข
This will be fun.
ต้องสนุกแน่เลย
I should at least do this.
อย่างน้อยก็ควรทำแบบนี้
Let's make an effort.
พยายามเข้า
Gosh, I'm so tired.
เฮ้อ เหนื่อยจัง
Maybe it's because I don't exercise,
หรือเป็นเพราะไม่ค่อยออกกำลังกายนะ
but my whole body hurts.
ปวดไปทั้งตัวเลย
Oh, Da-On.
อ้าว ประธาน
You're here early.
มาเร็วนะ
Yes, but why are you here?
ครับ แต่ประธานมาที่นี่ทำไม
Oh, I'm here to help you clean.
อ๋อ ฉันมาช่วยทำความสะอาด
You don't need to.
ไม่ต้องก็ได้
It's hard to do it alone.
ทำคนเดียวเหนื่อยจะตาย
You looked really tired just now.
เมื่อกี้นายดูเหนื่อยสุด ๆ เลย
So you saw everything?
เห็นทุกอย่างเลยสินะ
Sit and take a break for a bit. Let's clean up together.
นั่งพักไปก่อนแล้วกัน ช่วยกันทำเถอะ
Where did you get that?
ไปเอานั่นมาจากไหนเหรอ
I got this from the bathroom.
อ๋อ เอามาจากห้องน้ำ
Okay.
โอเค
If you're not still resting when I get back, you'll be in trouble.
ถ้ากลับมาแล้วนายไม่พัก ต้องโดนดุนะ
Okay.
ครับ
I'll be right back.
เดี๋ยวฉันมานะ
Staying like this is more uncomfortable.
อยู่แบบนี้อึดอัดกว่าอีก
I was taking a break.
ผมพักอยู่ครับ
Haven't you read the fairy tale "Snail Bride"?
ไม่เคยอ่านนิทานเรื่องเจ้าสาวหอยทากเหรอ
The snail bride runs away when it gets caught.
เจ้าสาวหอยทากวิ่งหนีเมื่อถูกจับได้
So?
แล้วไง
Leave because I caught you.
ไปซะ เพราะฉันจับได้แล้ว
I'm not leaving.
ฉันไม่ไป
This is the student council room. You're not a member.
นี่ห้องสภานักเรียน นายไม่ใช่สมาชิกสักหน่อย
- You're unauthorized... - Do you...
- นายไม่ได้รับอนุญาต... - นาย...
not have any feelings?
ไม่มีความรู้สึกเหรอ
What?
อะไรนะ
I came here early in the morning to sweep, wipe, and mop.
ฉันมากวาด เช็ด ถูตั้งแต่เช้า
Last night, I fell asleep while looking up...
เมื่อคืนก็เผลอหลับไปตอนหาข้อมูล
machines that squeeze mops.
ถังรีดไม้ถูพื้น
I really felt like I became a snail bride these past few days,
ฉันรู้สึกเหมือนเป็นเจ้าสาวหอยทาก ในช่วงสองสามวันที่ผ่านมา
but don't you feel like...
แต่นายไม่รู้สึกชอบฉัน
you might like me...
หรืออาจจะชอบฉัน
or come to like me?
บ้างเลยเหรอ
No.
ไม่
So don't bother wasting your time.
เพราะงั้นอย่าเสียเวลาเลย
There's no way...
ฉันไม่มีทาง
I will end up liking you.
ชอบนาย
Do you have anything left to say?
มีอะไรจะพูดอีกไหม
Are you protesting?
ประท้วงเหรอ
No. It's not that.
เปล่า ไม่ใช่อย่างนั้น
The thing is... I can see...
คือว่า ผมนาย...
a spider in your hair.
มีแมงมุมอยู่
Gosh, it wasn't a spider. It was a piece of dust.
อ้าว ไม่ใช่แมงมุมแฮะ ก็แค่เศษฝุ่น
What? Why are you laughing?
อะไรล่ะ หัวเราะทำไม
It's funny.
ก็มันตลก
By the way,
ว่าแต่
do your ears get red easily?
นายเป็นคนหูแดงง่ายเหรอ
You...
นาย...
What?
หือ
I really hate you.
ฉันล่ะเกลียดนายจริง ๆ
My gosh, that jerk.
ไอ้บ้านั่น
I'm getting mad because he keeps saying he hates me.
เอาแต่พูดว่าเกลียดนี่มันน่าโมโหจริง ๆ
I was wondering who was making Shin-Woo's ears so red. It was you.
ก็ว่าอยู่ว่าใครทำให้รองประธาน หูแดงแปร๊ดขนาดนั้น นายนี่เอง
What?
อะไรนะ
It's been a while since I saw that.
ไม่ได้เห็นมานานแล้วนะ
I can't believe you managed to awaken that monster. This is a big deal.
นายดันปลุกปีศาจนั่นขึ้นมาซะได้ เรื่องใหญ่แน่
- What do you mean? - What?
- หมายความว่าไง - หือ
Gosh, no. It's a good thing.
ไม่มีอะไรหรอก เป็นเรื่องดี
A good thing?
เรื่องดีเหรอ
You know that good things come at a cost, right?
รู้ใช่ไหมว่าเรื่องดีมีราคาที่ต้องจ่าย
Hey, I have no idea what you're talking about.
คือว่านะ ฉันไม่รู้ว่านายพูดอะไร ตั้งแต่เมื่อกี้แล้ว
You woke up the monster,
นายปลุกปีศาจให้ตื่น
so you must put it back to sleep.
ฉะนั้นต้องทำให้มันหลับดังเดิม
(Administration)
(ห้องสภานักเรียน)
Then is he a new hired hand? No.
งั้นก็เป็นลูกจ้างชั่วคราวเหรอ ไม่สิ
Our new member?
สมาชิกใหม่เหรอ
He's not an official member yet.
เขายังไม่ได้เป็นสมาชิกอย่างเป็นทางการ
We reflected Shin-Woo's opinion, and he'll be a temporary member for a month.
เราพิจารณาความเห็นของชินอูแล้ว เขาจะเป็นสมาชิกชั่วคราวหนึ่งเดือน
- Let's applaud Shin-Woo. - Don't you dare.
- ปรบมือให้ชินอูหน่อย - อย่าเชียวนะ
How well you clean for a month will decide on whether or not you'll join.
การทำความสะอาดของนายในหนึ่งเดือน จะเป็นตัวตัดสินว่าจะได้เข้าไหม
Don't meddle and help him clean.
พี่ก็อย่าช่วยให้เสียเรื่องล่ะ
Okay. Don't worry.
รู้ ๆ ไม่ต้องห่วง
- You have to do it alone. - I get it.
- นายต้องทำคนเดียว - รู้แล้วน่า
What changed your mind?
แล้วทำไมนายเปลี่ยนใจขึ้นมาล่ะ
You seemed like you'd never allow it.
เห็นทำเหมือนให้ตายก็ไม่อนุญาต
The student council room is really dirty.
ก็ห้องสภานักเรียนสกปรกมาก
You should be cleaner.
น่าจะสะอาดกว่านี้หน่อย
Gosh. Okay. Fine.
แหม ขอรับ ทราบแล้วขอรับ
- Are you going to keep joking around? - I'm so sorry, Mr. Vice President.
- จะล้อเล่นอีกนานไหม - ขออภัยขอรับ ท่านรองประธาน
Goodness.
เฮอะ
Woo Tae-Gyeong. Let's get along.
อูแทกยอง มาสนิทกันไว้นะ
We do a lot in student council,
สภานักเรียนมีงานหลายอย่าง
so we'll get close quickly while working on it together.
เราคงสนิทกันไวระหว่างที่ทำงานด้วยกัน
If this place is ever messy, it'll be over.
ถ้าห้องรกเมื่อไรก็จบเลยนะ
We won't go easy on you.
เราไม่ปล่อยไปหรอก
I get it.
รู้แล้ว
Shin-Woo. That's enough. Stop picking on him on his first day.
ชินอู พอได้แล้ว อย่าหาเรื่องเขาตั้งแต่วันแรกสิ
Right. Didn't he clean this morning too?
นั่นสิ เมื่อเช้าเขาก็ทำความสะอาดไม่ใช่เหรอ
Gosh.
ว้าว
You can eat off this table.
เอาข้าวมาคลุกกินบนโต๊ะยังได้เลย
On my way in, I saw that the recycling bin was full.
ตอนเดินเข้ามา ฉันเห็นถังขยะรีไซเคิลเต็มแล้วนะ
I'll go throw it out.
เดี๋ยวไปทิ้ง
Why? Do you not want to do it?
ทำไมล่ะ ไม่อยากทำเหรอ
My gosh. Thank you so much for letting me be a temporary member.
แหม เป็นพระคุณอย่างสูง ที่ให้กระผมเป็นสมาชิกชั่วคราว
Let's see.
โอเค
It's okay.
ไม่เป็นไรครับ
I can do it alone.
ผมทำคนเดียวได้
This is really heavy.
หนักจริง ๆ
Let's go.
ไปกันเถอะ
(Saebit Boys High School)
(โรงเรียนมัธยมปลายชายแซบิต)
It'll be hard to do everything alone. Let's do it together.
ทำคนเดียวคงลำบาก ต่อไปทำด้วยกันนะ
Thank you.
ขอบคุณครับ
There's no need to thank me.
ไม่ต้องขอบคุณหรอก
You can be comfortable around me. You're our member.
ทำตัวสบาย ๆ ก็ได้ นายเป็นสมาชิกของเราแล้ว
I'm not an official member.
ผมไม่ใช่สมาชิกทางการสักหน่อย
You'll be a member soon, and we'll spend more time together.
อีกไม่นานก็ใช่ เราจะได้ใช้เวลาด้วยกันมากขึ้น
Okay.
ครับ
Oh, right. Did you volunteer at Saebit Center last year?
จริงสิ ปีที่แล้วนายเป็นอาสาสมัคร ที่ศูนย์แซบิตใช่ไหม
Yes.
ครับ
I knew it. I went there too.
ว่าแล้ว ฉันก็ไปมาเหมือนกัน
I thought you familiar, and I was thinking about it...
ก็ว่าหน้าคุ้น ๆ พอเห็นนายเมื่อวาน
when I remembered.
ก็นึกขึ้นมาได้
Didn't you read picture books for Ant Class?
นายอ่านหนังสือภาพให้ห้องมดใช่ไหม
Yes, I did. How interesting.
ใช่ครับ น่าสนใจจัง
You're the first person who remembered me.
ประธานเป็นคนแรกเลยที่จำผมได้
I have really good memory.
ฉันความจำดีเป็นเลิศ
In any case, if you ever need help, just call me.
เอาเป็นว่า ถ้าต้องการความช่วยเหลือ ก็เรียกหาได้ทุกเมื่อ
Thank you.
ขอบคุณครับ
Also, you may be a temporary member for now,
อีกอย่าง ตอนนี้นายอาจจะเป็น สมาชิกชั่วคราว
but you'll be a real member soon, so don't worry about it.
แต่อีกไม่นานก็ได้เป็นสมาชิกตัวจริง ไม่ต้องกังวลไปหรอก
I'm not sure. Someone really hates me.
ไม่รู้สิครับ มีคนเกลียดผมเข้าไส้เลย
Shin-Woo is a good kid. He's kind and considerate too.
ชินอูเป็นเด็กดี ใจดีและคิดถึงคนอื่นด้วย
Everyone looks nice to nice people,
ใคร ๆ ก็ดูนิสัยดีไปหมดในสายตาคนดี
and they understand why they behave that way.
แถมยังเข้าใจสาเหตุที่ทำตัวแบบนั้นด้วย
That's why I won't believe you.
ผมก็เลยไม่เชื่อประธาน
Am I nice?
ฉันเป็นคนดีเหรอ
Yes. Based on what I've seen so far.
ครับ จากที่เห็นจนถึงตอนนี้
Gosh, I'm so touched.
โอ้โฮ ซึ้งนะเนี่ย
But Shin-Woo is nicer than me.
แต่ชินอูดีกว่าฉันอีก
I'm not sure about that.
เรื่องนั้นก็นะ
Right. You won't know each other until you get close.
ใช่ ถ้ายังไม่ถึงขั้นสนิทกันก็ไม่รู้หรอก
You should use this chance to get close.
ใช้โอกาสนี้สนิทกันไว้สิ
Okay. I'll try.
ครับ ผมจะพยายาม
Oh, right. You can't get closer to him than me.
อ้อ แต่สนิทมากกว่าฉันไม่ได้นะ
I should get going.
ฉันต้องไปแล้ว
I'll see you again.
ไว้เราค่อยเจอกันนะ
Yes. I'm on my way.
อือ ฉันกำลังไป
I'll be there soon. Okay.
เดี๋ยวตามไป โอเค
He keeps saying "we".
เอาแต่พูดว่า "เรา" อยู่นั่น
But he has really good memory.
แต่เขาก็ความจำดีจริง ๆ
How did he remember that?
จำเรื่องนั้นได้ยังไงนะ
What?
อะไรเหรอ
What? How long were you in there?
อะไรเนี่ย อยู่ตรงนั้นตั้งแต่เมื่อไร
No. Why are you there?
ไม่สิ ไปอยู่ตรงนั้นทำไม
My specialty is sleeping unseen.
การนอนแบบไม่มีใครเห็น เป็นความสามารถพิเศษของฉัน
During class, I sleep behind the lockers,
ระหว่างเรียน ฉันนอนหลังล็อกเกอร์
During gym class, I pretend to get water and sleep in the lounge.
ช่วงคาบพละ ก็ทำเหมือนไปดื่มน้ำ แล้วนอนในห้องพัก
- I see. - Why do you look so depressed?
- อ๋อ - แต่ทำไมดูหดหู่นักล่ะ
Is life hard?
ชีวิตลำบากเหรอ
A bit.
นิดหน่อย
That's true.
ก็จริง
Life is like that. Nothing comes easy.
ชีวิตก็แบบนี้แหละ ไม่มีอะไรได้มาง่าย ๆ
But you don't need to worry.
แต่ไม่ต้องกังวลไป
Why? Because you have me.
ทำไมรู้ไหม เพราะมีฉันอยู่ทั้งคน
Okay. Ask me anything.
โอเค ถามมาได้เลย
What does Noh Shin-Woo like?
โนชินอูชอบอะไรเหรอ
Oh, right.
ยากเลย
Unfortunately, he doesn't like anything.
แย่หน่อยที่เขาไม่ชอบอะไรเลย
He's hopeless.
เกินเยียวยา
But...
แต่...
one thing is for certain.
มีสิ่งหนึ่งที่แน่นอน
Noh Shin-Woo is bothered by you.
นายกวนใจโนชินอู
It's a good thing.
ถือเป็นเรื่องดีนะ
Just trust me. I know everything.
เชื่อใจฉันเถอะ ฉันรู้ทุกอย่าง
My gosh.
สุดยอดเลย
We were just talking about you. Want to join?
เรากำลังพูดถึงนายอยู่พอดี จอยด้วยไหม
What? What are you doing?
อะไร ทำอะไรน่ะ
- Let's go? - Where?
- ไปกันเถอะ - ไปไหน
Just follow me.
ตามมาเถอะน่า
Let's take our temporary member with us.
พาสมาชิกชั่วคราวไปด้วยสิ
We could become close.
เราจะได้สนิทกันไง
Why bother getting close?
จะสนิทไปทำไม
He's not even a real member. There's no point.
ไม่ใช่ตัวจริงสักหน่อย จะลำบากเพื่อ
He's going to leave soon anyway.
อีกเดี๋ยวก็ต้องไปอยู่ดี
You're such a heartless man.
ไอ้ผู้ชายไร้หัวใจ
Hey. Tae-Gyeong. I'll see you later.
นี่ สมาชิกชั่วคราว ไว้เจอกันนะ
You can ask me questions later.
สงสัยอะไรค่อยมาถาม
You know that I know...
รู้ใช่ไหม ฉันรู้...
everything.
ทุกอย่าง
Gosh. He has such a bad personality, and he's immature too.
โห นิสัยห่วยแตก แถมยังทำตัวเป็นเด็กอีก
Oh, my.
อ้าว
Have you seen Sin Da-On?
เห็นชินดาอนบ้างไหม
Why aren't you answering me?
ทำไมไม่ตอบล่ะ
Can't you hear me?
ไม่ได้ยินหรือไง
Right. I didn't see him.
อือ ไม่เห็น
He's not even answering my calls. Where is he?
ไม่ยอมรับสายเลย หายไปไหนนะ
Hey.
นี่
This is an all-boys school.
ที่นี่เป็นโรงเรียนชายล้วนนะ
So what?
แล้วไง
What? Well...
อะไรนะ คือว่า
Aren't girls not allowed to be at an all-boys school?
ผู้หญิงเข้าโรงเรียนชายล้วนไม่ได้ ไม่ใช่เหรอ
Why not? Don't you know me?
ทำไมล่ะ ไม่รู้จักฉันเหรอ
I don't.
ไม่รู้
I come here every day.
ฉันมาที่นี่ทุกวัน
You should be able to tell by looking at the things in here, so why don't you?
เห็นของในนี้ก็น่าจะรู้แล้วสิ แล้วทำไมไม่รู้ล่ะ
Aren't you a member?
นายไม่ได้เป็นสมาชิกเหรอ
You said you didn't see him.
ไหนว่าไม่เห็นเขาไง
What?
อะไรนะ
Why do I smell Sin Da-On's cologne on you?
ทำไมได้กลิ่นน้ำหอมชินดาอนบนตัวนายล่ะ
(Light on Me)
=Light on Me=
Our president is good at everything, but he can't refuse.
ประธานของเราเก่งทุกอย่าง แต่ปฏิเสธไม่เป็น
I asked why you hate me so much.
(ฉันถามว่าทำไมถึงเกลียดฉันนัก)
It bothers me and gets on my nerves.
(มันกวนใจแล้วก็กวนโมโห)
My gosh, you're so annoying.
(เฮ้อ น่ารำคาญชะมัด)
Noh Shin-Woo?
โนชินอูเหรอ
Where are you going?
จะไปไหน
Wake up, Woo Tae-Gyeong. Woo Tae-Gyeong!
ฟื้นสิ อูแทกยอง อูแทกยอง
(Light on Me)
=Light on Me=